good morning everyone
um
this is a
very
brief
um
condensed down version of a presentation
i've heard twice now from a gentleman in
our organization that is extremely
successful
he's fascinating to listen to
and
it just every time we hear him
he's just really exciting for us
so these are the highlights and i mean
just the highlights
it's going to sound a little bit choppy
only because like it's very high level
view
but there's some great inspiration in
here and i hope that you'll all walk
away
with a little bit more of the reason why
and how you do your business
do you remember this story about the
little girl who went to her mom and said
why do you cut the ends off the ham mom
well because your grandma did
so she goes to grandma grandma why
didn't you cut the ends off the ham
well because gigi did
she goes to gigi
why did you cut the ends off the ham
so it would fit the hand
simple she drilled down to that why
why and we always have any questions why
for our clients and our customers
so how do you find your customers why
it's by listening and i'm really really
listening
we all know that you should be listening
and talking 10
that's why god gave you two ears and one
mouth
and you have to ask those questions
why and drill down just like that little
girl did
it doesn't matter what you sell
every client is different and every
client has a different need a want and a
why
when i sell financial security the
client doesn't care what i use to get
the job done for them
just that their financial security is
set
there's no mistakes
i can call an annuity a snuffle up a
gift
as long as it gets the job done
when you find out what's important to
your client
your job then is to execute that great
idea
we've all heard of apple
and we all know that apple is definitely
different
do you want to buy an air conditioner
don't buy some advertising
when i say i make sure your financial
security is set that means no mistakes
i'm not selling a product
i'm selling the future
so how do you get your ideas heard
how does this sound
let's schedule a meeting to go over your
file your issue or your concern
i'll watch the back of your head wrong
or hey i've got an idea a concept or a
solution that i want to share with you
can i come by
because you've already listened to your
story by asking their why
and found out what's important to them
you can execute the great idea that
you're paid for
our clients are busy people and their
priorities are definitely different than
ours
we have to accommodate that and we have
to work around that
perfect and be consistent with your
process
when what you do is routine and second
nature you don't have to think about the
little things you can focus them on each
individual client
that means
repeating your introduction
repeating your confirmation calls
and your interviews
the same thing over and over and over
again
you don't have to think about it then
how great you will be
will be driven by how emotionally
connected you are to your beliefs
here's an example
we've all heard the first line of his
speech
i have a dream
he didn't tell people what to do
he didn't even say he had a plan
he simply brought his belief to life
dick white this man and son here did
something above himself
dick's son rick came home from school
one day and said he wanted to do a
charity 5k for a lacrosse player that
was injured in an accident
dick told him he'd push him
even though he was 40 and he hadn't done
any running or racing before
rick had such a great time in that race
he said he didn't feel like he had a
disability
instead it felt like he was flying
dick knew then that he had to keep
helping his son keep that feeling
they completed over 1100 events
32 of them were boston marathons this
year was their last one
dick now 72
but a teammate of theirs will continue
to push rick in those races
the history of our world has been
determined this way
by doing something above ourselves
your biography will be your destiny
destiny if you live in the past
if you're not doing something to make
somebody else's life better you're
wasting your time
the secret of success lies in the
ability to understand the other person's
point of view
by henry ford
people can claim to fail due to a lack
of resources
but really it's a lack of
resourcefulness
these are some of the daily practices
that our guest speaker
keeps every day
which i found very simple
very easy
you gotta dress the part
you gotta know the product
know your competition product
get out and see the people
make a difference and do something above
yourself
in the end don't deal with everyone
but just deal with the people who
believe in what you do
you